Come on! You're almost there!
Keep it up!
Nine hours, 12 minutes.
Not bad given the conditions
you had to trudge through.
[EREN sighs]
Thought we were
dead out there.
Dammit. Nobody said training
was gonna be this rough.
Anyone else
not feel their legs?
Why won't they
let us inside already?
[SASHA] I bet they're busy
laying out a massive
banquet for us as we speak.
[REINER] Hey!
You guys seen Christa?
[EREN]
Huh?
Not for a while.
She was with Daz,
and he wasn't doing so good.
Yeah, well he's not here.
Ymir isn't back yet either.
[MARCO] They're probably
mixed in with the last squad.
[REINER] That's just it.
Thomas was leading
the last squad.
Says they never saw them.
[All gasp]
Whoa, hold on.
Do you think they're lost?
Ooof. Man, if they
get stuck out there
in this snowstorm,
they're done for.
Son of a--!
Eren!
I have to go back out there
and try to find 'em!
[MARCO]
I'm with you!
[FEMALE INSTRUCTOR 30A]
In the cabin. Now.
[EREN]
But, Christa and--
We know. A rescue team will
be sent out at first light.
They'll have frozen
to death by then!
Do you want
more people to die?
Dammit.
[YMIR]
Christa.
Seriously, give it up.
This is pointless.
No it's not.
[YMIR] Dumb bastard's got one
foot in the grave as it is.
Nobody to blame but
himself if you ask me.
Should've known
how much he could handle
before trying
to boost his score.
Some people just aren't
cut out to be soldiers.
He'll be long gone
by the time you make it
to the foot of that mountain.
Rate we're going, we'll be
lucky not to join him.
It's a zero sum game.
Way I see it,
we've got two choices.
Leave Daz to the elements
and save our own skin,
or die a cozy little trio.
What's it gonna be?
You left one out.
Third option:
you're completely wrong.
I reach base in plenty
of time to save his life
and by morning this is
all a bad memory.
There's no reason
for you to stick with me.
We'll only slow you down.
You'll make it back
a lot faster on your own.
Daz and I'll be
right behind you.
Go on ahead.
[CHRISTA gasps]
So, uh...
You got something against
asking me for help or what?
Know what I think?
I think saving this moron
is the furthest thing
from your mind.
[YMIR] You're not
worried about Daz.
You're just using him
as an excuse to die.
This is how you want
your story to end. Right?
What a shame. Here I thought
you were the good girl.
Of course, if you can
make it look like you were
trying to save his life,
no one will be the wiser.
Hey. They'll remember
you as a hero
who fearlessly
sacrificed herself.
He's a small
price to pay, right?
If you're a selfish bitch.
[CHRISTA gasps]
That's not--!
I never meant--
That's not me.
[CHRISTA]
It's just...
I know you.
You're the mistress' daughter
with the price on her head.
How could you possibly?
[YMIR] Uh-huh.
There go any doubts I had.
Let's just say
I have a knack for being
in the wrong place
at the right time.
Snuck inside a church
in the interior once
scrounging around
for whatever might
keep me alive another week.
Quite a story
I got treated to.
Apparently a high-ranking
noble produced more heirs
than his people
were comfortable with.
An illegitimate girl
was floating around
they all feared might
come out of nowhere one day
and claim a share
in his legacy.
Some wanted her dead,
some wanted to strip her
of the family name
and hide her
among peasant stock.
In the end, clever
bastards forced her
to join the Cadet Corps.
Don't worry, sweetheart.
Your true identity
is safe with me.
I haven't told a soul
and I don't plan to.
So was, was your
whole reason for joining
the Cadet Corps
just to find me?
Why would you even care?
[YMIR inhales]
I dunno. Maybe I relate
to your struggle.
[CHRISTA gasps]
So we... have more
in common than I thought?
Well, uh.
You could say that.
I'm why you're...
a soldier?
Could be.
I'm not positive.
Uh, actually, no.
So why, then?
Did you want us
to become friends?
Ha! You have
got to be joking.
[YMIR] The only thing we have
in common is a second chance.
Look, don't try to read
anything else into it, okay?
Unlike you, I embraced
the name I was born with.
If I throw it away and reject
who I am, then they win.
I intend to live my life.
Make my name mean something.
Trust me, there's no
revenge in the world
sweeter than that.
Look at yourself, Christa--
or whoever you are.
You've been a victim
all your life,
and how do you
get your revenge?
By becoming your own victim!
Screw you and this
stupid death wish!
If you kill yourself, you'll be
doing exactly what they want!
I-- That's not how--
I just--
I didn't mean
to get us into this
and now there's
nothing we can do.
[YMIR]
Bullshit.
The base is a
straight drop from here.
[YMIR] I say we
dump him off the cliff.
[CHRISTA gasps]
It's possible
he'll survive the fall.
If they find him
then he might be okay.
Sure, it's a long shot,
but that's what
we're dealing with.
Unless we're
due for a miracle,
even if you live
to drag him down there
all you'll have in tow
by the time you make it
is a frozen corpse.
But, if he falls
he'll die for certain!
Enough of this shit!
[CHRISTA] What are
you doing? Put me down!
I'll handle Daz,
you get moving!
[CHRISTA yells]
[Grunts]
[Distant rumble]
[CHRISTA gasps and panting]
[CHRISTA]
No.
Ymir!
Wait! Please!
What's going on?
Where did they--?
[EREN] It's better if you guys
let me do this alone.
Like our instructors said--
We don't want more people
to die than may already have.
That's precisely why
I'm coming with you.
I can't just sit around
here and do nothing.
[REINER] Really?
What the hell is this?
[EREN] Look,
don't try to stop me!
You're, uh, gonna need
a lot more gear.
You can't do this
on your own.
You'll end up just like the
folks you're trying to rescue.
The more eyes you've got
in your search party,
the better, right?
Well, we--
I suppose we could use
all the help we can get.
[CONNY] Great.
Then count us in, too.
Sounds like the storm's
letting up a little bit.
We should be okay.
I brought some extra
rations just in case!
Thanks, guys.
[Distant rumble]
What was that?
An avalanche?
Look, somebody's coming!
[CHRISTA breathes laboringly]
Ymir?
It's about time.
You decide to take
the scenic route?
I told Reiner and the gang
I'd wait out here
to be your welcoming
committee, so--
Yeah, I know.
Stupid move on my part.
Daz! Is he--?
[CHRISTA] From all
the way up there?
But you didn't have
any rope on you.
And even if you did, how?
It would've taken
hours to repel down!
Yeah, all right.
If I have to trust someone,
then it might as well be you.
Just... gimme your word.
When the day comes
for me to reveal myself
to everyone, promise.
Promise to take back your
name and live your life.
[Gasps]
[CHRISTA]
Ymir!
[YMIR]
Christa. We're the same.
I used to curse the day
I was born, just like you.
The world despised me
for having the gall to exist.
Heh. I thought the only
way to put things right
was to give up my life.
But even then,
what I wished for
more than anything...
...was to be given
a second chance.
A chance to finally
live for myself!
[Roars]
[CONNY] Talk to me. Somebody
tell me it's all a dream.
Ymir.
[Gasps]
It was her that day.
She's the one.
[Screams]
Thank you, Reiner. I--
[Yelps]
Stop, you're hurting me!
[CONNY]
Hey! Take it easy, man!
That's enough! Let go! Let go!
I'm so sorry!
It's okay.
Tell me the truth.
You had to have been
in on all this.
Ymir's a Titan.
How could you not know?
She never told me.
We were inseparable.
And yet, I had no idea.
I mean, how?
[Roars]
Not sure what to think.
All this time she's been
keeping it under wraps
and we never suspected
a damn thing.
Yeah.
Well, it's possible
she didn't know.
Eren was caught off guard.
He had no clue
till he transformed.
Then again, Ymir did
seem to have a plan.
Wait a second;
are you trying to say that
Ymir is a threat?
Maybe. It's a hell of
a power to hide.
How she'll use it
is anybody's guess.
For all we know
she could've been
on their side all along.
[Roars]
[CHRISTA gasps]
[CHRISTA]
Ymir!
Whoa! What is she doing?
[Roars]
Oh, come on!
You're kidding, right?
She's worried about
the tower falling down?
Exactly. She didn't
have to stay.
She could've chosen to escape.
Nothing's keeping her here.
And still...
She's fighting.
It's us. She's risking
her life for us!
Who are you?
Why are you
doing this? Why?
Don't you die on me!
Not in a hovel
like this, damn you!
Whoa!
[CHRISTA] You want to be
the hero all of a sudden?
Ha! Hoping to go out
in a blaze of glory?
Don't make me laugh!
Too late to
think about heaven now!
You're a selfish bitch
and you know it!
You'll die protecting
this stupid tower!
Tear it to pieces!
Live for yourself!
[CONNY]
Christa!
[Intense music plays]
Shit! Brace yourselves,
people. This is happening!
Yeah! Atta girl!
Wanna live? Grab on tight.
[Rumble]
[Coughs]
[Both gasp]
They're still not dead?
Hey, ugly! You've got
a job to finish!
Ymir!
[TITAN YMIR panting]
That's not good.
[TITANS roar]
[Squelching]
They're eating her!
[CHRISTA]
No. No, please.
Christa, wait!
[CHRISTA]
Ymir! Don't do this to me!
Damn it! We had
a deal, remember?
Hold on! I still haven't
told you my name!
I promised you!
[CHRISTA]
No! I still haven't...
[MIKASA] Christa,
all of you, get back.
It's okay. Let us
take care of this.
Mikasa!
[ALL gasp]
[HANGE] Disperse and
canvas the area!
The rest of you
follow me to where
the Titans are gathering
and cut them down!
Got it!
Wait! You're not
part of the offensive!
Die!
Ha-ha!
My very first ODM kill!
[EREN hollers]
[KEIJI] Idiot!
I told you to fall back!
Right! I'm sorry, sir!
Ow, damn.
[CONNY]
Hey! Eren!
We found 'em!
[Yells]
Can't be. She's really...?
[CHRISTA]
Ymir.
Just as promised.
My real name is Historia.
♪ Closing Song